Finding Aid for George R. Averill papers, 1928-1969
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
George R. Averill papers 1928-1969
Averill, Geoarge R., 1893-1971.
2 linear feet and 30 oversize volumes
85781 Aa 2; AC
Editor and publisher of the Birmingham Eccentric; correspondence, scrapbooks, and other materials relating to his career.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was received from George R. Averill in 1969 and from Mrs. Averill in 1974. ( Donor no. 4741 )
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
George R. Averill was editor and publisher of the Birmingham Eccentric.
The collection consists of correspondence, newspaper clippings, scrapbooks, and other materials concerning Averill's newspaper career, his support of Senator Arthur H. Vandenberg, especially in the election of 1934, and his support of other Republican candidates, particularly Wilber M. Brucker and Herbert Hoover. Some of Averill's correspondents include Roscoe O. Bonisteel, Wilber M. Brucker, James J. Couzens, Chase S. Osborn, Frank M. Sparks, and Arthur H. Vandenberg.
Subjects:
Birmingham eccentric.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Michigan--Politics and government--1929-1938.; American newspapers--Michigan--Birmingham.; Republican Party (Mich.); Special Vandenberg Committee of Michigan Newspapermen.; United States. Congress--Elections, 1934.; United States--Politics and government--1933-1945.; United States--Politics and government--1929-1933.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Averill, George R., 1893-1971.; Birmingham (Mich.)--Business enterprises.; Birmingham eccentric.; Business enterprises--Michigan--Birmingham.; Interiors--Newspaper industry--1921.; MacArthur, Douglas, 1880-1964.; Newspaper industry--Michigan--Birmingham.; Printing industry.
Contributors:
Bonisteel, Roscoe O. (Roscoe Osmond), b. 1888.; Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.; Couzens, James, 1872-1936.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860; Sparks, Frank Melville, 1877-.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Correspondence
  - 1928 (Box 1)
  - 1931 (Box 1)
  - 1932-1933 (Box 1)
  - 1934 (Box 1)
  - 1935 (Box 1)
  - January-February 1936 (Box 1)
  - March-December 1936 (Box 1)
  - 1937-1948 (Box 1)
- Subject Files
  - Reminiscences concerning Senator Arthur Vandenberg, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Petitions from newspapermen requesting Vandenberg run for re-election, 1933, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea concerning Vandenberg, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea concerning Wilber Brucker (Box 1)
  - Correspondence concerning the 75th anniversary edition of the Eccentric (Box 1)
  - Letter to the editor, 1943-1961 (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning the Freedom of Information Committee of the Michigan Press Association, 1952-1954 (Box 1)
  - Bulletins published by the Eccentric, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - The "Town Crier", 1943-1953 (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea concerning President Herbert Hoover's re-election campaign, 1932, 8 folders (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbooks of the "Ears" columns, 1932-1963, 7 volumes (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks of newspaper editorials, 30 volumes (Volume 1)
- Other materials
  - Speeches (Box 2)
    (unprocessed)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 2)
  - Miscellanea (Box 2)
  - Photographs, 2 envelopes (Box 2)
    (include photos of exterior and of interior of Eccentric building, 1921 and 1950s; photos of visit of General Douglas MacArthur to Birmingham, ca. 1951; and portraits)